<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Visual Studio on dwmkerr.com</title><link>https://dwmkerr.com/tags/visual-studio/</link><description>Recent content in Visual Studio on dwmkerr.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-uk</language><copyright>Copright &amp;copy; Dave Kerr</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2014 11:40:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dwmkerr.com/tags/visual-studio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Managing Vsix Deployments with Powershell</title><link>https://dwmkerr.com/managing-vsix-deployments-with-powershell/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2014 11:40:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dwmkerr.com/managing-vsix-deployments-with-powershell/</guid><description>tl;dr - vsix-tools fixes the &amp;lsquo;Invalid Multiple Files in VSIX&amp;rsquo; issue on the Visual Studio Gallery and lets you set vsix version numbers with Powershell.
I maintain a reasonably large project called SharpGL. This project contains two Vsix packages (Visual Studio Extensions), each of which contains project templates for Visual Studio.
If you have ever worked with Vsix files before you might have noticed that the tools for them in Visual Studio seem a little flaky - but even more so is that Visual Studio Gallery site that you have to use to upload your extensions.</description></item><item><title>Recursive read lock acquisitions not allowed in this mode</title><link>https://dwmkerr.com/recursive-read-lock-acquisitions-not-allowed-in-this-mode/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2013 02:17:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dwmkerr.com/recursive-read-lock-acquisitions-not-allowed-in-this-mode/</guid><description>If you are using the following combination of tools:
Recursive read lock acquisitions not allowed in this mode.I'm lost on the root cause of this, but it does seem that the project I'm working on has files set to read-only by something regularly, perhaps Visual Studio is trying to make Git more TFS-y by locking things all over the place. Whatever the cause, I've found that the following usually helps:</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio Deployment Projects - an Update</title><link>https://dwmkerr.com/visual-studio-deployment-projects-an-update/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2013 12:18:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dwmkerr.com/visual-studio-deployment-projects-an-update/</guid><description>I received the following message in my inbox the other day:
&amp;lsquo;[Uservoice declined - Bring back the basic setup and deployment project type Visual Studio Installer.&amp;rsquo;
Some readers may recall my post on the frustrating removal of the simple deployment project from Visual Studio. Unfortunately, with this message, they have closed the Uservoice request to bring back the basic setup projects (the request is at http://visualstudio.uservoice.com/forums/121579-visual-studio/suggestions/3041773-bring-back-the-basic-setup-and-deployment-project-).
It's rare for me to blog or comment on products like visual studio, to complain or evangelise about features and so on, but in this case as the previous post had received some interest I thought I'd write an update.</description></item><item><title>Web Deploy - Could not connect to the remote computer</title><link>https://dwmkerr.com/publish-web-web-deploy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2013 09:22:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dwmkerr.com/publish-web-web-deploy/</guid><description>Using Web Deploy is a nice and easy way to publish websites and web applications with Visual Studio. However, I found one thing that can be a bit of a blocker, that didn't seem to be explained anywhere very well.
Let's imagine I administer a webserver that hosts the site www.something.com. I've installed the Remote Management tools for IIS and the Web Deploy stuff, and have also configured the site to allow Web Deploy.</description></item><item><title>Switch Updated</title><link>https://dwmkerr.com/switch-updated/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2013 14:43:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dwmkerr.com/switch-updated/</guid><description>There have been some problems with the version of Switch uploaded to the Visual Studio Gallery. I've created a new version of Switch (1.4) and uploaded this - it works fine now, for Visual Studio 2008, 2010 and 2012.
You can find out more about this extension on the Switch Page.</description></item><item><title>The Visual Studio Experimental Instance</title><link>https://dwmkerr.com/the-visual-studio-experimental-instance/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2013 14:41:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dwmkerr.com/the-visual-studio-experimental-instance/</guid><description>Working on some addins lately has taught me a few really useful tricks about debugging in Visual Studio. I'll update this post over time.
The Experimental InstanceVery useful to know - the experimental instance loads its extensions from a special folder, and debugging extensions drops them there. The location is:
%UserProfile%\AppData\Local\Microsoft\VisualStudio\10.0Exp\Extensions\</description></item><item><title>Deployment Projects in Visual Studio 2012</title><link>https://dwmkerr.com/deployment-projects-in-visual-studio-2012/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2012 05:40:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dwmkerr.com/deployment-projects-in-visual-studio-2012/</guid><description>[Note: They aren't bringing setup projects back, see http://www.dwmkerr.com/2013/06/visual-studio-deployment-projects-an-update/]
As part of Microsoft's ongoing campaign to reduce the usability of their tools for anyone who isn't working in exactly the way they want, Visual Studio 2012 no longer comes with the ability to create setup and deployment projects.
This is a pretty serious change. For anyone who is developing client applications, then an installer is pretty critical. Now the feature set in the VS deployment projects was fairly small - they were aimed towards making pretty basic, lean installers.</description></item><item><title>Go Offline Extension for Visual Studio 2010</title><link>https://dwmkerr.com/go-offline-extension-for-visual-studio-2010/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2012 10:54:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dwmkerr.com/go-offline-extension-for-visual-studio-2010/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Come on MS - Improve MFC</title><link>https://dwmkerr.com/come-on-ms-improve-mfc/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2012 09:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dwmkerr.com/come-on-ms-improve-mfc/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Create Item Templates in Visual Studio</title><link>https://dwmkerr.com/create-item-templates-in-visual-studio/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2012 06:29:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dwmkerr.com/create-item-templates-in-visual-studio/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Switch</title><link>https://dwmkerr.com/switch/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2012 03:53:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dwmkerr.com/switch/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Extending Visual Studio Part 1 - Code Snippets</title><link>https://dwmkerr.com/extending-visual-studio-part-1-code-snippets/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 05:20:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dwmkerr.com/extending-visual-studio-part-1-code-snippets/</guid><description/></item><item><title>How to Debug a Visual Studio Extension</title><link>https://dwmkerr.com/how-to-debug-a-visual-studio-extension/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2011 11:11:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dwmkerr.com/how-to-debug-a-visual-studio-extension/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>