<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>dwmkerr.com</title><link>http://example.org/</link><description>Recent content on dwmkerr.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-uk</language><copyright>Dave Kerr</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 07:25:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Effective Shell Part 7: The Subtleties of Shell Commands</title><link>http://example.org/effective-shell-7-shell-commands/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 07:25:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/effective-shell-7-shell-commands/</guid><description>In this chapter, we'll take a look at the various different types of shell commands that exist and how this can affect your work.
By the end of this chapter, you might even be able to make sense of the horrifying and perfectly syntactically valid code below:
which $(where $(what $(whence $(whereis who)))) Part 1: Navigating the Command Line Part 2: Become a Clipboard Gymnast Part 3: Getting Help Part 4: Moving Around Part 5: Interlude - Understanding the Shell Part 6: Everything You Don't Need to Know About Job Control Part 7: The Subtleties of Shell Commands What Are Commands?</description></item><item><title>Effective Shell Part 6: Everything You Don't Need To Know About Job Control</title><link>http://example.org/effective-shell-6-job-control/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 08:26:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/effective-shell-6-job-control/</guid><description>Job control is a feature of most shells, which is generally not particularly intuitive to work with. However, knowing the basics can help prevent you from getting yourself into a tangle, and can from time to time make certain tasks a little easier.
In this chapter, we'll look at the main features of job control, why it can be a problematic, and some alternatives.
Part 1: Navigating the Command Line Part 2: Become a Clipboard Gymnast Part 3: Getting Help Part 4: Moving Around Part 5: Interlude - Understanding the Shell Part 6: Everything You Don't Need to Know About Job Control Part 7: The Subtleties of Shell Commands What Is Job Control?</description></item><item><title>Effective Shell Interlude: Understanding the Shell</title><link>http://example.org/effective-shell-part-5-understanding-the-shell/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 09:22:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/effective-shell-part-5-understanding-the-shell/</guid><description>This is the first &amp;lsquo;interlude&amp;rsquo; in my Effective Shell series. These interludes give some background, history or more flavour to some of the topics.
Part 1: Navigating the Command Line Part 2: Become a Clipboard Gymnast Part 3: Getting Help Part 4: Moving Around Part 5: Interlude - Understanding the Shell Part 6: Everything You Don't Need to Know About Job Control Part 7: The Subtleties of Shell Commands This one should be high-level enough for even non-technical readers to enjoy (or at least understand!</description></item><item><title>Effective Shell 4: Move Around!</title><link>http://example.org/effective-shell-4-moving-around/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 09:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/effective-shell-4-moving-around/</guid><description>This is the fourth part of my Effective Shell series, a set of practical examples of ways to be more efficient with everyday tasks in the shell or at the command line.
Part 1: Navigating the Command Line Part 2: Become a Clipboard Gymnast Part 3: Getting Help Part 4: Moving Around Part 5: Interlude - Understanding the Shell Part 6: Everything You Don't Need to Know About Job Control Part 7: The Subtleties of Shell Commands In this article we'll look at the key elements of navigation in the shell.</description></item><item><title>Dynamic and Configurable Availability Zones in Terraform</title><link>http://example.org/dynamic-and-configurable-availability-zones-in-terraform/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 21:24:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/dynamic-and-configurable-availability-zones-in-terraform/</guid><description>When building Terraform modules, it is a common requirement to want to allow the client to be able to choose which region resources are created in, and which availability zones are used.
I've seen a few ways of doing this, none of which felt entirely satisfactory. After a bit of experimentation I've come up with a solution which I think really works nicely. This solution avoids having to know in advance how many availability zones we'll support.</description></item><item><title>A portable and magic-free way to open Pull Requests from the Command Line</title><link>http://example.org/a-portable-and-magic-free-way-to-open-pull-requests-from-the-command-line/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 09:17:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/a-portable-and-magic-free-way-to-open-pull-requests-from-the-command-line/</guid><description>This little bash snippet will let you open a GitHub or GitLab pull request from the command line on most Unix-like systems (OSX, Ubuntu, etc), without using any magic libraries, ZSH tricks or other dependencies.
Here's how it looks in action OSX:
And Ubuntu:
The script is available as the gpr.sh gist. You can also find it in my dotfiles, in the git.sh file.
The Script Here's the script in its entirety:</description></item><item><title>Manipulating Istio and other Custom Kubernetes Resources in Golang</title><link>http://example.org/manipulating-istio-and-other-custom-kubernetes-resources-in-golang/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 21:34:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/manipulating-istio-and-other-custom-kubernetes-resources-in-golang/</guid><description>In this article I'll demonstrate how to use Golang to manipulate Kubernetes Custom Resources, with Istio as an example. No knowledge of Istio is needed, I'll just use it to demonstrate the concepts!
Istio is a highly popular Service Mesh platform which allows engineers to quickly add telemetry, advanced traffic management and more to their service-based applications.
One interesting element of how Istio works is that when deployed into a Kubernetes cluster, many key configuration objects are handled as Custom Resources.</description></item><item><title>Procedural Smiles - Animating SVG with pure JavaScript</title><link>http://example.org/procedural-smiles-animating-svg-with-pure-javascript/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2018 23:36:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/procedural-smiles-animating-svg-with-pure-javascript/</guid><description>I recently needed to be able to generate a simple face image, with the face being able to scale from happy to sad.
(Why I needed to do this is a long story!)
This gave me the opportunity to have a play with SVG, which is something I've not done in a while and always wished I could spend more time with. You can see the result below, move the slider to see the smile animate:</description></item><item><title>Patching Kubernetes Resources in Golang</title><link>http://example.org/patching-kubernetes-resources-in-golang/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 06:33:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/patching-kubernetes-resources-in-golang/</guid><description>Recently I needed to be able to quickly adjust the number of replicas in a Kubernetes Replication Controller. The original solution I'd seen pulled down the spec, modified it, then updated it. There's a better way!
There's a patch API for Kubernetes resources. Patching resources is faster and easier than pulling them and updating the spec wholesale. However, the documentation is a little limited.
After some trial and error I got it working, here's the solution.</description></item><item><title>Speaking</title><link>http://example.org/page/speaking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 01:54:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/page/speaking/</guid><description>VoxxedDays Singapore 2018 Devops - What does devops culture mean for engineers?
Video Slides DevOpsDays Jakarta 2018 The Universe as Code - What Programming Can Teach us about Maths, Science and Philosophy
SpeakerDeck
Serverless Summit - 2017 Build a chatbot in ten minutes!
SpeakerDeck
DevOpsDays Singapore 2017 Microservices to Monoliths - Practical tips for CI/CD and DevOps in the Microservice world
SlideShare | SpeakerDeck
JSChannel 2016 Effective Node Debugging
In this talk I demonstrate techniques for debugging NodeJS applications.</description></item><item><title>mongo-monitor - a simple CLI to monitor your MongoDB cluster</title><link>http://example.org/mongo-monitor-cli/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 20:09:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/mongo-monitor-cli/</guid><description>The mongo-monitor CLI is a lean and simple tool to check the status of a MongoDB server or cluster. The code is on GitHub:
github.com/dwmkerr/mongo-monitor
Here's how it looks in action:
In this animation I am monitoring a simple sharded cluster, and running some example maintenance operations, adding a node to a replicaset, stepping down a primary and shutting down a replicaset node.
A simple CLI which shows the status in real-time can be very useful to keep open when performing admin, letting you see how your changes affect the cluster as you work on it.</description></item><item><title>The Death of Microservice Madness in 2018</title><link>http://example.org/the-death-of-microservice-madness-in-2018/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 10:52:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/the-death-of-microservice-madness-in-2018/</guid><description>En Español | Reddit Thread | Hacker News Thread
Microservices became a very popular topic over the last couple of years1. &amp;lsquo;Microservice madness&amp;rsquo; goes something like this:
Netflix are great at devops. Netflix do microservices. Therefore: If I do microservices, I am great at devops.
There are many cases where great efforts have been made to adopt microservice patterns without necessarily understanding how the costs and benefits will apply to the specifics of the problem at hand.</description></item><item><title>Effective Shell Part 3: Getting Help</title><link>http://example.org/effective-shell-part-3-getting-hepl/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 09:05:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/effective-shell-part-3-getting-hepl/</guid><description>This is the third part of my Effective Shell series - practical examples of ways to be more efficient with everyday tasks in a shell.
Part 1: Navigating the Command Line Part 2: Become a Clipboard Gymnast Part 3: Getting Help Part 4: Moving Around Part 5: Interlude - Understanding the Shell Part 6: Everything You Don't Need to Know About Job Control Part 7: The Subtleties of Shell Commands In this article I'll show you how to quickly get help when working with tools in the shell, without disrupting your flow!</description></item><item><title>Integrating OpenShift and Splunk for Docker Container Logging</title><link>http://example.org/integrating-openshift-and-splunk-for-logging/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 07:15:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/integrating-openshift-and-splunk-for-logging/</guid><description>In this article I'm going to show you how to set up OpenShift to integrate with Splunk for logging in a Docker container orchestration environment.
These techniques could easily be adapted for a standard Kubernetes installation as well!
The techniques used in this article are based on the Kubernetes Logging Cluster Administration Guide. I also found Jason Poon's article Kubernetes Logging with Splunk very helpful.
First, clone the Terraform AWS OpenShift repo:</description></item><item><title>Effective Shell Part 2: Become a Clipboard Gymnast</title><link>http://example.org/effective-shell-part-2-become-a-clipboard-gymnast/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 09:57:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/effective-shell-part-2-become-a-clipboard-gymnast/</guid><description>This is the second part of my Effective Shell series, which contains practical tips for using the shell to help with every day tasks and be more efficient:
Part 1: Navigating the Command Line Part 2: Become a Clipboard Gymnast Part 3: Getting Help Part 4: Moving Around Part 5: Interlude - Understanding the Shell Part 6: Everything You Don't Need to Know About Job Control Part 7: The Subtleties of Shell Commands In this article I'll show you how you can use the shell as an efficient tool to compliment how you use the clipboard.</description></item><item><title>Effective Shell Part 1: Navigating the Command Line</title><link>http://example.org/effective-shell-part-1-navigating-the-command-line/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 23:05:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/effective-shell-part-1-navigating-the-command-line/</guid><description>This is the first part of a series I am writing which contains practical tips for using the shell more effectively.
Part 1: Navigating the Command Line Part 2: Become a Clipboard Gymnast Part 3: Getting Help Part 4: Moving Around Part 5: Interlude - Understanding the Shell Part 6: Everything You Don't Need to Know About Job Control Part 7: The Subtleties of Shell Commands I can't think of a better place to start than navigating the command line.</description></item><item><title>A utility to help you wait for ports to open</title><link>http://example.org/a-utility-to-help-you-wait-for-ports-to-open/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 22:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/a-utility-to-help-you-wait-for-ports-to-open/</guid><description>There are occasions where you might need to have scripts or commands which wait for TCP/IP ports to open before you continue.
I've come across this need again and again when working with microservices, to make my life easier I've created a little utility called wait-port which will wait for a port to open:
It's built in Node, the project is open source, open for contributions and ready to use:</description></item><item><title>Tips and Tricks for Beautifully Simple Mobile App CI</title><link>http://example.org/tips-and-tricks-for-beautifully-simple-mobile-app-ci/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 11:14:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/tips-and-tricks-for-beautifully-simple-mobile-app-ci/</guid><description>In this article I'm going to demonstrate some simple tips and tricks which will help you build and maintain beautifully simple mobile build pipelines. These techniques can be applied to different mobile app technologies and integrated into almost any build system:
Each tip is demonstrated in the sample apps in the dwmkerr/beautifully-simple-app-ci repo.
The Challenges of Mobile App CI Tip 1 - Embrace Makefiles for Consistency Tip 2 - Control Version Numbers with a &amp;lsquo;Touch&amp;rsquo; Command Tip 3 - Control App Icons with a &amp;lsquo;Label&amp;rsquo; Command Tip 4 - Support Configurable App Ids Tip 5 - Document, Document, Document Conclusion The Challenges of Mobile App CI Conceptually, a mobile app CI pipeline is pretty simple:</description></item><item><title>Get up and running with OpenShift on AWS</title><link>http://example.org/get-up-and-running-with-openshift-on-aws/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 07:47:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/get-up-and-running-with-openshift-on-aws/</guid><description>OpenShift is Red Hat's platform-as-a-service offering for hosting and scaling applications. It's built on top of Google's popular Kubernetes system.
Getting up and running with OpenShift Online is straightforward, as it is a cloud hosted solution. Setting up your own cluster is a little more complex, but in this article I'll show you how to make it fairly painless.
The repo for this project is at: github.com/dwmkerr/terraform-aws-openshift.
Creating the Infrastructure OpenShift has some fairly specific requirements about what hardware it runs on1.</description></item><item><title>Creating a Resilient Consul Cluster for Docker Microservice Discovery with Terraform and AWS</title><link>http://example.org/creating-a-resilient-consul-cluster-for-docker-microservice-discovery-with-terraform-and-aws/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2017 07:10:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/creating-a-resilient-consul-cluster-for-docker-microservice-discovery-with-terraform-and-aws/</guid><description>In this article I'm going to show you how to create a resilient Consul cluster, using Terraform and AWS. We can use this cluster for microservice discovery and management. No prior knowledge of the technologies or patterns is required!
The final code is at github.com/dwmkerr/terraform-consul-cluster. Note that it has evolved somewhat since the time of writing, see the Appendices at the end of the article for details.
Consul, Terraform &amp;amp; AWS Consul is a technology which enables Service Discovery1, a pattern which allows services to locate each other via a central authority.</description></item><item><title>Using Slack for Server Development</title><link>http://example.org/using-slack-for-server-development/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 01:25:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/using-slack-for-server-development/</guid><description>I recently found a surprisingly helpful approach for server-side development which uses Slack in a creative way.
The Problem The scenario can be roughly simplified to this:
We are building a mobile app and application server. This will take data from a user, transform it and then pass it to the enterprise system processing.
The problem is that the enterprise system doesn't exist yet!
Now this is not too much of a challenge, the first thing we did was build a simple mock of the enterprise system in Node.</description></item><item><title>Simple Continuous Integration for Docker Images</title><link>http://example.org/simple-continuous-integration-for-docker-images/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2016 05:14:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/simple-continuous-integration-for-docker-images/</guid><description>In this article I'm going to demonstrate a few tips and tricks which can make your life easier when you are building or maintaining Dockerfiles.
The need for a Build Pipeline Do we really need any kind of continuous integration or build pipeline for Dockerfiles?
There will be cases when the answer is no. However, if the answer to any of the following questions is &amp;lsquo;yes&amp;rsquo;, it might be worth considering:</description></item><item><title>Run Amazon DynamoDB locally with Docker</title><link>http://example.org/run-amazon-dynamodb-locally-with-docker/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 08:06:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/run-amazon-dynamodb-locally-with-docker/</guid><description>tl;dr: Run DynamoDB locally using Docker:
docker run -d -p 8000:8000 dwmkerr/dynamodb Try it out by opening the shell, localhost:8000/shell:
That's all there is to it!
DynamoDB Amazon DynamoDB is a NoSQL database-as-a-service, which provides a flexible and convenient repository for your services.
Building applications which use DynamoDB is straightforward, there are APIs and clients for many languages and platforms.
One common requirement is to be able to run a local version of DynamoDB, for testing and development purposes.</description></item><item><title>Effective Node.js Debugging</title><link>http://example.org/effective-node-js-debugging/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2016 01:36:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/effective-node-js-debugging/</guid><description>If you are interested in improving your Node.js debugging skills, then check out my talk at the recent JSChannel 2016 conference in Bangalore:
Comments and observations are always welcome!</description></item><item><title>Testing the Docker for Mac Beta</title><link>http://example.org/testing-the-docker-for-mac-beta/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2016 10:45:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/testing-the-docker-for-mac-beta/</guid><description>I've finally had a chance to install the new Docker for Mac Beta and give it a whirl. In this article I'm going to talk a bit about how Docker works, the challenges of running Docker on a Mac or Windows and how the new Beta helps.
Below: The welcome message for the new Docker for Mac app
So What is Docker for Mac? If you don't know what Docker is, check out my article Learn Docker by Building a Microservice or the lovely What is Docker page from the docs.</description></item><item><title>Is it worth persevering with Golang?</title><link>http://example.org/is-it-worth-persevering-with-golang/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 22:10:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/is-it-worth-persevering-with-golang/</guid><description>I recently decided to try out the Go Programming Language, by building a little project called google-it which let's me run a google search from a terminal:
The idea behind the project is simple - avoid jumping into a browser if you need to quickly look up something which you can find in the first line of a Google search result. The idea is to try and stay in the zone.</description></item><item><title>What's your Vim Name?</title><link>http://example.org/whats-your-vim-name/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 08:58:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/whats-your-vim-name/</guid><description>I'm a few weeks into moving to Vim as my main editor, I've stopped crying and shaking mostly (at least about my editing ability).
Now I'm wondering: what's your Vim name? And who's got the best one?
As far as I can work out, my Vim name is:
Replace everything from the cursor to the end of the line with 've'. Which is what happens if I get bored and type my name (Dave) into Vim.</description></item><item><title>Quick Tip: Sending Newlines with cURL</title><link>http://example.org/quick-tip-sending-newlines-with-curl/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 22:12:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/quick-tip-sending-newlines-with-curl/</guid><description>Yikes, this took far too long to figure out!
I have a service which takes plain text multi-line input and outputs an object for each line, something like this:
Input
Line 1 Line 2 Line 3 Output
[ {line: &amp;quot;Line 1&amp;quot;}, {line: &amp;quot;Line 2&amp;quot;}, {line: &amp;quot;Line 3&amp;quot;} ] There's a bit more to it than that, but that's the gist.
I want to test my service with cURL, trying:
curl --data &amp;quot;Line 1\nLine 2\nLine 3&amp;quot; \ -H &amp;quot;Content-Type: text/plain&amp;quot; localhost:3000/parse This did not work.</description></item><item><title>Moving from React + Redux to Angular 2</title><link>http://example.org/moving-from-react-redux-to-angular-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2016 09:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/moving-from-react-redux-to-angular-2/</guid><description>I've just finished working on a very large project written in React and Redux. The whole team were new to both and we loved them.
I'm going to share my experiences of experimenting in Angular 2 with you, from the point of view of someone who needs a pretty compelling reason to move away from my JSX and reducers.
The Journey So Far Let me highlight a few key moments in my UI development experiences, to give a bit of context to my ramblings.</description></item><item><title>Learn Docker by building a Microservice</title><link>http://example.org/learn-docker-by-building-a-microservice/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 08:54:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/learn-docker-by-building-a-microservice/</guid><description>If you are looking to get your hands dirty and learn all about Docker, then look no further!
In this article I'm going to show you how Docker works, what all the fuss is about, and how Docker can help with a basic development task - building a microservice.
We'll use a simple Node.js service with a MySQL backend as an example, going from code running locally to containers running a microservice and database.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started with React &amp; ES6</title><link>http://example.org/getting-started-with-react/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2015 19:44:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/getting-started-with-react/</guid><description>Feeling like having a go with Facebook's hugely popular React framework but not sure where to start?
In this post I'm going to build a simple React application from scratch - using ECMAScript 6.
We'll put together the bare minimum skeleton of a site and keep the folder structure free of noise and clutter so that you can focus on the app code and not the tooling!
The simple app we'll build is at github.</description></item><item><title>Manipulating JSON Web Tokens (JWTs)</title><link>http://example.org/modifying-a-jwt-in-a-node-application/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2015 14:45:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/modifying-a-jwt-in-a-node-application/</guid><description>I've been writing a couple of web services lately that use Auth0 for identity management. It's a great platform that makes working with different identity providers a breeze.
One thing that I couldn't work out how to do at first was to quickly build a new JWT1from an existing token. I wanted to take my current token, add some more data to it and return it to the user. So here's a &amp;lsquo;why&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;how&amp;rsquo;.</description></item><item><title>The Best Module System for AngularJS Applications</title><link>http://example.org/the-best-module-system-for-angularjs-applications/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2015 14:47:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/the-best-module-system-for-angularjs-applications/</guid><description>I was working on a small and simple application built with AngularJS the other day. As with most applications like this, I start with a single JavaScript file caled app.js and no module system.
In the past I've used RequireJS with AngularJS. It's an awful mistake. It leads to a big jump in complexity with no benefts. Angular apps don't work well with AMDs, so really your are using RequireJS to combine files into one big file.</description></item><item><title>Failures Connecting from Elastic Beanstalk servers to MongoDB on EC?</title><link>http://example.org/failures-connecting-from-elastic-beanstalk-servers-to-mongodb-on-ec/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2015 10:34:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/failures-connecting-from-elastic-beanstalk-servers-to-mongodb-on-ec/</guid><description>tl;dr?
Check your mongodb.conf bind_ip settings to make sure that you're not allowing connections only from localhost.
This may just end up being the first part of a wider troubleshooting guide, but this is one I've spent a few hours fixing, after assuming I was making terrible mistakes with my security groups.
If you find you cannot connect to your MongoDB server from an EB app server (or anything for that matter), before you spend ages checking your Elastic IP, VPC and Security Group config, don't forget that you may have simply used bind_ip in your config file.</description></item><item><title>Fixing Memory Leaks in AngularJS and other JavaScript Applications</title><link>http://example.org/fixing-memory-leaks-in-angularjs-applications/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2015 14:35:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/fixing-memory-leaks-in-angularjs-applications/</guid><description>Dealing with memory leaks in JavaScript applications can be a complex process. In this article I'm going to show you how to identify whether you have memory leaks, analyse them and ultimately resolve them.
I'm using an AngularJS application to demonstrate the concepts and approaches, but much of this material applies to any JavaScript application.
Understanding Memory Leaks What is a Memory Leak? Why is a Memory Leak Bad?</description></item><item><title>The Only AngularJS Modal Service You'll Ever Need</title><link>http://example.org/the-only-angularjs-modal-service-youll-ever-need/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2014 00:48:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/the-only-angularjs-modal-service-youll-ever-need/</guid><description>If you need modals in an AngularJS application, look no further. I'll show you how to use the Angular Modal Service to add Bootstrap Modals or your own custom modals to your application.
See it in a fiddle or check out a full set of samples online.
Contents [Using the Angular Modal Service](#UsingTheAngular ModalService) A Quick Example Design Goals How It Works Wrapping Up Using the Angular Modal Service Here's how you can use the Angular Modal Service to add a bootstrap modal to your application.</description></item><item><title>Practical AngularJS Part 2 – Components of an AngularJS Application</title><link>http://example.org/practical-angularjs-part2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2014 14:55:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/practical-angularjs-part2/</guid><description>Welcome to Part 2 of Practical AngularJS. I’m going to introduce you to some of the core components of an angular app. These are:
Controllers Filters Directives Services Views &amp;amp; Routes We’re not going to be going into detail – just taking a look at what each of these components are and where they fit into the structure of an app. We’ll be going into detail for each of them in later articles.</description></item><item><title>Practical AngularJS</title><link>http://example.org/practical-angularjs/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2014 14:48:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/practical-angularjs/</guid><description>This series focuses on building applications with AngularJS. It assumes no prior knowledge.
Part 1 – Introducing AngularJS
What is AngularJS? What’s it for and when should we use it? We look into the basics of AngularJS – controllers, models and scopes, as well as how to use common directives like ng-model and ng-repeat. We see how client side logic is improved with AngularJS and how we can handle unit testing.</description></item><item><title>AngularJS Promises - The Definitive Guide</title><link>http://example.org/promises-in-angularjs-the-definitive-guide/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2014 12:06:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/promises-in-angularjs-the-definitive-guide/</guid><description>Promises are a core feature of AngularJS - whether you understand them or not, if you use AngularJS you've almost certainly been using them for a while.
In this post I'm going to explain what promises are, how they work, where they're used and finally how to use them effectively.
Once we've got the core understanding of promises, we'll look at some more advanced functionality - chaining and resolving promises when routing.</description></item><item><title>Better Specifications</title><link>http://example.org/better-specifications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2014 14:58:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/better-specifications/</guid><description>Specifications are absolutely key to the success of a project.
Unless you have a good definition of what your project is supposed to be, there's no way you can deliver it. A specification is the contract between you and the client, the basis for technical designs, quality assurance test plans, operational readiness, and much more.
I'm not going to talk about how different teams do specs, what works and what doesn't work.</description></item><item><title>Blogging with Ghost</title><link>http://example.org/blogging-with-ghost/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2014 04:35:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/blogging-with-ghost/</guid><description>tl;dr Ghost is a blogging platform well worth considering if your blog is all about development.
I've been having some gripes with WordPress as a platform for blogging lately. For development focused blogs like this one, there are some things about it that make writing posts just a little bit clunky. For example:
Syntax Higlightling is always going to use plugins with various shortcode formats. This works, but your raw blog text becomes quite specific to a certain implementation.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>http://example.org/page/about/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2014 14:59:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/page/about/</guid><description>I have been developing software for many years. Starting out in C, moving into C++ and then C# and the .NET Framework. More recently I've been working with JavaScript and the MEAN stack. I have worked as a web developer, web designer and a software developer for everything from device drivers to full enterprise applications.
I am also the secretary and co-founder of the charity Namaste – Children’s Homes Nepal.</description></item><item><title>Practical AngularJS Part 1 – Introducing AngularJS</title><link>http://example.org/practical-angularjs-part1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2014 14:48:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/practical-angularjs-part1/</guid><description>In this series of articles I'm going to be working with AngularJS, a fantastic framework from Google that helps you rapidly build web applications. We'll see how AngularJS can be used to speed up your development and help you write cleaner, more testable code.
Introducing AngularJS First of all an introduction is in order.
AngularJS is a lightweight JavaScript framework, primarily for building single page web applications. The idea behind applications like these is that rather than the &amp;lsquo;traditional&amp;rsquo; way of writing web applications which would involve using server side technologies to render the user interface and send it to the user, we handle all of the presentation logic on the client side.</description></item><item><title>Managing Vsix Deployments with Powershell</title><link>http://example.org/managing-vsix-deployments-with-powershell/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2014 11:40:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/managing-vsix-deployments-with-powershell/</guid><description>tl;dr - vsix-tools fixes the &amp;lsquo;Invalid Multiple Files in VSIX&amp;rsquo; issue on the Visual Studio Gallery and lets you set vsix version numbers with Powershell.
I maintain a reasonably large project called SharpGL. This project contains two Vsix packages (Visual Studio Extensions), each of which contains project templates for Visual Studio.
If you have ever worked with Vsix files before you might have noticed that the tools for them in Visual Studio seem a little flaky - but even more so is that Visual Studio Gallery site that you have to use to upload your extensions.</description></item><item><title>Practical AngularJS Part 2</title><link>http://example.org/practical-angularjs-part-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2014 15:29:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/practical-angularjs-part-2/</guid><description>I'm going to be working in F# almost exclusively for a short while, so before I throw myself into that I wanted to wind up my Practical AngularJS Part 2 article. It's ready to rock here:
Practical AngularJS Part 2 - Components of an AngularJS ApplicationIn this article we get a brief introduction to what's in the toolkit for an angular developers - filters, controllers, services, directives, views and routes. I don't go into too much detail, we're just seeing what the different components are.</description></item><item><title>Langton's Ant in Javascript</title><link>http://example.org/langtons-ant-in-javascript/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2013 10:47:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/langtons-ant-in-javascript/</guid><description>Langton's Ant is a great simulation to write to play with a language. Just today I've completed my Langton's Ant write up and published it on the CodeProject, you can see the article at Learn JavaScript Part 3 - Angularjs and Langton's Ant.
There are some interesting things in the article for angular too - a look at using directives for custom elements, how to handle both the DOM and Angular loading correctly, and timers and intervals.</description></item><item><title>A great read for JavaScript newcomers</title><link>http://example.org/a-great-read-for-javascript-newcomers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2013 06:10:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/a-great-read-for-javascript-newcomers/</guid><description>A superb article by Colin Eberhardt has just been published on the CodeProject, called &amp;lsquo;Understanding JavaScript Object Creation Patterns&amp;rsquo;.
This article should be on the reading list of anyone who's new to JavaScript or not familiar with how objects and prototypes work. It takes you step by step through the basics all the way to protoypes and classes.
The article is at:
http://www.codeproject.com/Articles/687093/Understanding-JavaScript-Object-Creation-PatternsI'd strongly recommend it!</description></item><item><title>Introducing Practical AngularJS</title><link>http://example.org/introducing-practical-angularjs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2013 16:16:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/introducing-practical-angularjs/</guid><description>I was recently at Devoxx in Antwerp, primarily because I wanted to get involved in some of the sessions that were being hosted by guys from the AngularJS team at Google. I've had a chance to work a little with Backbone and KnockoutJS and had been recently deliberately holding off looking at AngularJS so I could hit the conference and workshops fresh and unencumbered with any preconceptions.
The sessions were great, and since then I've been working on a couple of projects that use Angular.</description></item><item><title>Space Invaders on the CodeProject</title><link>http://example.org/space-invaders-on-the-codeproject/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 12:24:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/space-invaders-on-the-codeproject/</guid><description>I'm currently writing a series of articles on the CodeProject called &amp;lsquo;Learn JavaScript&amp;rsquo; and am pleased to say that the latest article is available now!
Learn JavaScript Part 2 - Space InvadersIn this article we take a look at how to create the classic space invaders game with plain JavaScript and HTML - no libraries or frameworks. You can see it in action on the page experiments/spaceinvaders. Check it out - as always, comments are welcome!</description></item><item><title>SharpShell 2.0</title><link>http://example.org/sharpshell-2-0/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2013 06:31:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/sharpshell-2-0/</guid><description>I have just released SharpShell 2.0 - you can get the release from sharpshell.codeplex.comor the new GitHub page at github.com/dwmkerr/sharpshell.
This release has been primarily a bugfixing release, but there is one very useful new feature, the Server Registration Manager tool (srm.exe). This is a standalone application that can be used to install and uninstall SharpShell servers.
This tool makes it much easier to deploy SharpShell servers. You can call the tool as a Custom Action in a MSI project, either by using Visual Studio 2010's installer project type, or a WiX project.</description></item><item><title>ConsoleControl and Happy Coders</title><link>http://example.org/consolecontrol-and-happy-coders/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2013 13:27:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/consolecontrol-and-happy-coders/</guid><description>Sometimes I write up an article and some code on the CodeProject and get a good response, other times it seems an article sinks beneath the waves without any notice. Looking over some emails the other day, I noticed that my ConsoleControl article had actually received a slow and steady response of extremely positive feedback - people are using it and suggesting improvements.
This is great, it's one of the things I love about the community of developers that I'm part of.</description></item><item><title>Space Invaders in JavaScript</title><link>http://example.org/space-invaders-in-javascript/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2013 12:04:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/space-invaders-in-javascript/</guid><description>If you take a look at theExperiments Pageyou'll see that there's a new entry - Space Invaders.
Space Invaders is a great little game to code if you're learning a new language or technology (and JavaScript is still very much in that category for me). I'll be writing up how I made the game on the CodeProject soon enough (if you're interested you can see how I made the starfield background in JavaScript).</description></item><item><title>Introducing Experiments</title><link>http://example.org/introducing-experiments/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2013 06:00:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/introducing-experiments/</guid><description>I'm staring a series of articles on learning Javascript (the first is available at http://www.codeproject.com/Articles/642499/Learn-JavaScript-Part-1-Create-a-Starfield). To help with this, I've created the Experimentspage. This page will host each of the things I've been playing with in the process of learning JavaScript and coming up with good topics for tutorials.
You can see the Experimentspage here, there's also a link at the top of the site. If you like it, please feel free to comment on this post or get in touch.</description></item><item><title>Node.js and Express - Strange Http Status Codes</title><link>http://example.org/node-js-and-express-strange-http-status-codes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2013 16:23:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/node-js-and-express-strange-http-status-codes/</guid><description>Testing the C# code showed me something that was a bit odd - GETs and POSTSs were working fine, but PUTs and DELETEs were showing an HTTP Status code of &amp;lsquo;1&amp;rsquo; (which isn't a valid code). Here's the what I was seeing:
Checking the node server showed the same thing - DELETEs were returning status 1.
The server code is very lightweight so it's quick to see what's going on:</description></item><item><title>Recursive read lock acquisitions not allowed in this mode</title><link>http://example.org/recursive-read-lock-acquisitions-not-allowed-in-this-mode/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2013 02:17:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/recursive-read-lock-acquisitions-not-allowed-in-this-mode/</guid><description>If you are using the following combination of tools:
Recursive read lock acquisitions not allowed in this mode.I'm lost on the root cause of this, but it does seem that the project I'm working on has files set to read-only by something regularly, perhaps Visual Studio is trying to make Git more TFS-y by locking things all over the place. Whatever the cause, I've found that the following usually helps:</description></item><item><title>Context Menu for Trello</title><link>http://example.org/context-menu-for-trello/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2013 05:40:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/context-menu-for-trello/</guid><description>I'm on holiday at the moment, back in sunny England. Holiday may not be the right term really, I'm mostly working through charity stuff (for my charity Namaste - Children's Homes Nepal) and company administration. I'm also starting working on a big new project, which is pretty exciting.
Anyway, I got a nice message from a fellow coder George Hahnwho has put together a pretty cool project that lets you send files directly to Trelloas an attachment to a card, or even as a new card.</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio Deployment Projects - an Update</title><link>http://example.org/visual-studio-deployment-projects-an-update/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2013 12:18:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/visual-studio-deployment-projects-an-update/</guid><description>I received the following message in my inbox the other day:
&amp;lsquo;[Uservoice declined - Bring back the basic setup and deployment project type Visual Studio Installer.&amp;rsquo;
Some readers may recall my post on the frustrating removal of the simple deployment project from Visual Studio. Unfortunately, with this message, they have closed the Uservoice request to bring back the basic setup projects (the request is at http://visualstudio.uservoice.com/forums/121579-visual-studio/suggestions/3041773-bring-back-the-basic-setup-and-deployment-project-).
It's rare for me to blog or comment on products like visual studio, to complain or evangelise about features and so on, but in this case as the previous post had received some interest I thought I'd write an update.</description></item><item><title>Web Deploy - Could not connect to the remote computer</title><link>http://example.org/publish-web-web-deploy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2013 09:22:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/publish-web-web-deploy/</guid><description>Using Web Deploy is a nice and easy way to publish websites and web applications with Visual Studio. However, I found one thing that can be a bit of a blocker, that didn't seem to be explained anywhere very well.
Let's imagine I administer a webserver that hosts the site www.something.com. I've installed the Remote Management tools for IIS and the Web Deploy stuff, and have also configured the site to allow Web Deploy.</description></item><item><title>Build Buttons for Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn, GitHub and More!</title><link>http://example.org/build-buttons-for-facebook-twitter-linkedin-github-and-more/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2013 02:34:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/build-buttons-for-facebook-twitter-linkedin-github-and-more/</guid><description>Recently I've been working on a small project called Build Buttons. Build Buttonsis a website that let's you quickly create buttons for sharing and promoting content. You can use Build Buttons to create Facebook &amp;lsquo;Like&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;Follow&amp;rsquo; buttons, LinkedIn &amp;lsquo;Share&amp;rsquo; buttons, Google +1 buttons, GitHub Star, Fork and Follow buttons and more. Here's how it works.
First, go to www.buildbuttons.com:
Now choose the kind of buttons you want, in this example we'll select &amp;lsquo;Social Media&amp;rsquo; from the top menu:</description></item><item><title>WPF and Visual Studio Addins</title><link>http://example.org/wpf-and-visual-studio-addins/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2013 01:36:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/wpf-and-visual-studio-addins/</guid><description>If at all possible nowadays, I write all my Windows UI code in WPF, it's just quicker and easier than WinForms. Recently however, I came across a situation that you should just avoid.
If you're developing addins for multiple versions of Visual Studio - don't use WPF for the Tools &amp;gt; Options windows. It's just noit going to place nice out of the box. This is because there's a lot of property page Win32 stuff going on in the host window that makes it hard to route messages properly - keyboard entry won't work correctly, tab order will be messed up and more, it's just not worth the pain.</description></item><item><title>Introducing Sil</title><link>http://example.org/introducing-sil/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2013 15:35:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/introducing-sil/</guid><description>For the last few weeks I've been trying to tie up a project I've been working on for a while called Sil. With lots of other things on my plate at the moment I haven't had much of a chance to work on it, but finally tonight I'm able to release the first version.
Sil is short for &amp;lsquo;See IL&amp;rsquo;, or &amp;lsquo;See Intermediate Language&amp;rsquo;. It's primarily an addin for Visual Studio (2010 and 2012) that lets you right click on some code and disassemble it.</description></item><item><title>Creating Addins - 'An error occurred, and the wizard could not generate the project.'</title><link>http://example.org/creating-addins-an-error-occurred-and-the-wizard-could-not-generate-the-project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2013 02:38:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/creating-addins-an-error-occurred-and-the-wizard-could-not-generate-the-project/</guid><description>When doing a little bit of work on a solution that contains a Visual Studio Addin the other day, I noticed that there's a little bit of an issue with Visual Studio. If you create an addin project and you get the message:
An error occurred, and the wizard could not generate the project. Verify that the programming language is properly installed.Then double check where you are creating your addin. If it is in a child folder of the solution, then this error can occur.</description></item><item><title>Getting Paths for Files in NUnit Tests</title><link>http://example.org/getting-paths-for-files-in-nunit-tests/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2013 05:22:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/getting-paths-for-files-in-nunit-tests/</guid><description>When using NUnit, sometimes you will want to access files in the test project. These might be xml files with data, assembly references or whatever. Now typically, NUnit will actually copy the files it thinks it needs into a temporary location. This causes the problem that you can then do things like use a relative path to get files in the project. You can use manifest resource streams but sometimes this just isn't suitable.</description></item><item><title>Introducing FireKeys</title><link>http://example.org/introducing-firekeys/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 11:11:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/introducing-firekeys/</guid><description>I don't know when I learnt that Windows + E opened up Windows Explorer. It must have been a while ago. But it's imprinted in my muscle memory, the number of times I hit that combo every day is probably quite high. But how many other hotkeys do I use? Asides from a few other functional ones, like Win + D, I don't use hotkeys so much. And I got to thinking, I'd love to open Google Chrome with a hotkey just like I do with explorer.</description></item><item><title>Spider Solitaire and Augmented Reality</title><link>http://example.org/spider-solitaire-and-augmented-reality/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 16:16:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/spider-solitaire-and-augmented-reality/</guid><description>A while ago, I made an implementation of Solitaire and Spider Solitaire using WPF and my Apex MVVM library. I wrote about it on the CodeProject, in an article called Solitaire and Spider Solitaire for WPF(imaginative title indeed).
Anyway, just recently I got a very interesting message from rupam rupam, who has made an augmented reality version of the project! In his application, you use your webcam to play the game physically by picking up cards with gestures.</description></item><item><title>Switch Updated</title><link>http://example.org/switch-updated/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2013 14:43:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/switch-updated/</guid><description>There have been some problems with the version of Switch uploaded to the Visual Studio Gallery. I've created a new version of Switch (1.4) and uploaded this - it works fine now, for Visual Studio 2008, 2010 and 2012.
You can find out more about this extension on the Switch Page.</description></item><item><title>The Visual Studio Experimental Instance</title><link>http://example.org/the-visual-studio-experimental-instance/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2013 14:41:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/the-visual-studio-experimental-instance/</guid><description>Working on some addins lately has taught me a few really useful tricks about debugging in Visual Studio. I'll update this post over time.
The Experimental InstanceVery useful to know - the experimental instance loads its extensions from a special folder, and debugging extensions drops them there. The location is:
%UserProfile%\AppData\Local\Microsoft\VisualStudio\10.0Exp\Extensions\</description></item><item><title>Samsung to develop software in-house</title><link>http://example.org/samsung-to-develop-software-in-house-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2013 05:15:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/samsung-to-develop-software-in-house-2/</guid><description>While the mobile phone market has long been based upon continuing hardware development, things are now changing and companies are having to keep up. The focus of the smartphone market is now moving towards software, rather than hardware and Samsung are taking note of this change. The South Korean technology company have decided to increase their game in order to be able to successfully compete with American technology giant, Apple. To do this, Samsung need to alter the way they create their products, by developing their own software as well as hardware.</description></item><item><title>Creating Info Tip Handlers with .NET</title><link>http://example.org/creating-info-tip-handlers-with-net/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2013 03:47:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/creating-info-tip-handlers-with-net/</guid><description>I have just added an article to the CodeProject that discusses how to create Info Tip shell extensions in .NET. These extensions are used by the shell to customise the tooltips shown over shell items.
The article shows how you can use SharpShell to very quickly create these extensions, you can find it at: http://www.codeproject.com/Articles/527058/NET-Shell-Extensions-Shell-Info-Tip-Handlers.
So just how easy does SharpShell make creating Shell Info Tip Handlers? The answer is pretty easy indeed.</description></item><item><title>SharpShell</title><link>http://example.org/sharpshell/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2013 16:28:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/sharpshell/</guid><description>SharpShell is a project that I have recently uploaded to CodePlex. This class library, and set of tools and samples, is designed to be a framework to enable rapid development of Shell Extensions using the .NET Framework. In time it may grow to contain some functionality for using Shell entities within managed applications (for example, allowing an Explorer context menu to be built dynamically for a given path).
Anyway, the code is all at sharpshell.</description></item><item><title>SharpGL 2.1</title><link>http://example.org/sharpgl-2-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2012 08:06:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/sharpgl-2-1/</guid><description>For those who are interested, I'm now starting development of SharpGL 2.1. SharpGL 2.1 will primarily be a release to implement features and fix bugs that users have added to the Codeplex site. The actual features and bugs that'll be sorted are on the CodePlex site - just search for release &amp;lsquo;SharpGL 2.1&amp;rsquo;.
This will also be the first release of SharpGL that will be published on Nuget.</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio Extensions and Menu Subitems</title><link>http://example.org/visual-studio-extensions-and-menu-subitems/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2012 00:21:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/visual-studio-extensions-and-menu-subitems/</guid><description>//Place the command on the tools menu. //Find the MenuBar command bar, which is the top-level command bar holding all the main menu items: Microsoft.VisualStudio.CommandBars.CommandBar menuBarCommandBar = ((Microsoft.VisualStudio.CommandBars.CommandBars)_applicationObject.CommandBars)[&amp;quot;MenuBar&amp;quot;];
//Find the Tools command bar on the MenuBar command bar: CommandBarControl toolsControl = menuBarCommandBar.Controls[toolsMenuName]; CommandBarPopup toolsPopup = (CommandBarPopup)toolsControl;
//This try/catch block can be duplicated if you wish to add multiple commands to be handled by your Add-in, // just make sure you also update the QueryStatus/Exec method to include the new command names.</description></item><item><title>XPath Studio - First Cut</title><link>http://example.org/xpath-studio-first-cut/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2012 16:11:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/xpath-studio-first-cut/</guid><description>I have just uploaded the first cut of my mini-project &amp;lsquo;XPath Studio&amp;rsquo;. This project is a small site that lets you choose a URL to a source webpage, and run any XPath query against it - showing the data that is returned from the query.
At the moment this blog has an issue with images so I cannot upload screenshots, but in the next few days they'll be there. Until then, you can try out XPath Studio by visiting:</description></item><item><title>Deployment Projects in Visual Studio 2012</title><link>http://example.org/deployment-projects-in-visual-studio-2012/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2012 05:40:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/deployment-projects-in-visual-studio-2012/</guid><description>[Note: They aren't bringing setup projects back, see http://www.dwmkerr.com/2013/06/visual-studio-deployment-projects-an-update/]
As part of Microsoft's ongoing campaign to reduce the usability of their tools for anyone who isn't working in exactly the way they want, Visual Studio 2012 no longer comes with the ability to create setup and deployment projects.
This is a pretty serious change. For anyone who is developing client applications, then an installer is pretty critical. Now the feature set in the VS deployment projects was fairly small - they were aimed towards making pretty basic, lean installers.</description></item><item><title>Goodbye BlogEngine.NET, Hello WordPress</title><link>http://example.org/goodbye-blogengine-net-hello-wordpress/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2012 09:04:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/goodbye-blogengine-net-hello-wordpress/</guid><description>I run my websites on a Windows Server. Years ago, when I started web development, I ran almost exclusively on LAMP (Linux, Apache, MySQL, PHP) setups, which worked great for the sites I was building.
As I got more involved in commercial development, most of the sites and services I was working on were C#, ASP, IIS and MSSQL Server focused. This is great for web development too.
When I moved onto a new, Windows based server, I decided that as I was running MSSQL Server and IIS on it, I would move my personal blog onto an ASP based platform - for this I chose BlogEngine.</description></item><item><title>The GAC Manager</title><link>http://example.org/the-gac-manager/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2012 08:44:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/the-gac-manager/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Changing Merge/Compare Tools in TFS</title><link>http://example.org/changing-mergecompare-tools-in-tfs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2012 07:56:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/changing-mergecompare-tools-in-tfs/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Go Offline Extension for Visual Studio 2010</title><link>http://example.org/go-offline-extension-for-visual-studio-2010/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2012 10:54:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/go-offline-extension-for-visual-studio-2010/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Samsung to develop software in-house</title><link>http://example.org/samsung-to-develop-software-in-house/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2012 04:57:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/samsung-to-develop-software-in-house/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Apex Part 2 - Adding Commands to an MVVM Application</title><link>http://example.org/apex-part-2-adding-commands-to-an-mvvm-application/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2012 07:43:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/apex-part-2-adding-commands-to-an-mvvm-application/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Apex Part 1 - Getting Started with the Apex SDK</title><link>http://example.org/apex-part-1-getting-started-with-the-apex-sdk/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2012 05:35:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/apex-part-1-getting-started-with-the-apex-sdk/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Come on MS - Improve MFC</title><link>http://example.org/come-on-ms-improve-mfc/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2012 09:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/come-on-ms-improve-mfc/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Could not load file or assembly 'System.Windows, Version=2.0.5.0, Culture=neutral, PublicKeyToken=7cec85d7bea7798e' or one of its dependencies.</title><link>http://example.org/could-not-load-file-or-assembly-system-windows-version2-0-5-0-cultureneutral-publickeytoken7cec85d7bea7798e-or-one-of-its-dependencies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2012 07:55:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/could-not-load-file-or-assembly-system-windows-version2-0-5-0-cultureneutral-publickeytoken7cec85d7bea7798e-or-one-of-its-dependencies/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Create Item Templates in Visual Studio</title><link>http://example.org/create-item-templates-in-visual-studio/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2012 06:29:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/create-item-templates-in-visual-studio/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Embedding a Console in a C# application</title><link>http://example.org/embedding-a-console-in-a-c-application/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2012 05:29:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/embedding-a-console-in-a-c-application/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Disabling Constraints with a Stored Procedure in Oracle</title><link>http://example.org/disabling-constraints-with-a-stored-procedure-in-oracle/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2012 06:20:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/disabling-constraints-with-a-stored-procedure-in-oracle/</guid><description/></item><item><title>SharpGL 2.0</title><link>http://example.org/sharpgl-2-0/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2012 03:42:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/sharpgl-2-0/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Using imp or exp as a SYSDBA</title><link>http://example.org/using-imp-or-exp-as-a-sysdba/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2012 07:21:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/using-imp-or-exp-as-a-sysdba/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Debugger:: An unhandled non-continuable exception was thrown during process load</title><link>http://example.org/debugger-an-unhandled-non-continuable-exception-was-thrown-during-process-load/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2012 06:54:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/debugger-an-unhandled-non-continuable-exception-was-thrown-during-process-load/</guid><description>// Exported class class MY_API MyClass { public:
// ...etc
};</description></item><item><title>Switch</title><link>http://example.org/switch/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2012 03:53:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/switch/</guid><description/></item><item><title>New Namaste Website</title><link>http://example.org/new-namaste-website/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2012 14:18:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/new-namaste-website/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Funky WPF - Enumerations and the Combo Box</title><link>http://example.org/funky-wpf-enumerations-and-the-combo-box/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2012 03:11:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/funky-wpf-enumerations-and-the-combo-box/</guid><description/></item><item><title>CodeProject MVP</title><link>http://example.org/codeproject-mvp/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2012 07:25:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/codeproject-mvp/</guid><description>As a great start to the new year I have been made a CodeProject MVP!
Have a look at my index of articles below:
http://www.codeproject.com/script/Articles/MemberArticles.aspx?amid=4259528Any suggestions for future articles are more than appreciated.</description></item><item><title>Downtime</title><link>http://example.org/downtime/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2012 02:57:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/downtime/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Extending Visual Studio Part 1 - Code Snippets</title><link>http://example.org/extending-visual-studio-part-1-code-snippets/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 05:20:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/extending-visual-studio-part-1-code-snippets/</guid><description/></item><item><title>How to Debug a Visual Studio Extension</title><link>http://example.org/how-to-debug-a-visual-studio-extension/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2011 11:11:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/how-to-debug-a-visual-studio-extension/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Composite Data Service Framework on CodeProject</title><link>http://example.org/composite-data-service-framework-on-codeproject/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2011 11:12:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/composite-data-service-framework-on-codeproject/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Getting Source Code Metrics from SVN</title><link>http://example.org/getting-source-code-metrics-from-svn/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2011 07:55:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/getting-source-code-metrics-from-svn/</guid><description/></item><item><title>IDataServiceMetadataProvider Entities Missing in $metadata</title><link>http://example.org/idataservicemetadataprovider-entities-missing-in-metadata/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2011 15:49:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/idataservicemetadataprovider-entities-missing-in-metadata/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Composite Data Service Framework</title><link>http://example.org/composite-data-service-framework/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2011 11:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/composite-data-service-framework/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Data Service Exception "Unauthorised" when connecting to Sharepoint OData</title><link>http://example.org/data-service-exception-unauthorised-when-connecting-to-sharepoint-odata/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2011 10:28:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/data-service-exception-unauthorised-when-connecting-to-sharepoint-odata/</guid><description>// Provide default credentials, without this authorisation will fail! dc.Credentials = System.Net.CredentialCache.DefaultCredentials;
// Etc&amp;hellip; var accounts = from a in dc.Accounts select a;</description></item><item><title>The "Name attribute is invalid" when adding a Service Reference to a Sharepoint OData Service</title><link>http://example.org/the-name-attribute-is-invalid-when-adding-a-service-reference-to-a-sharepoint-odata-service/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2011 10:19:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/the-name-attribute-is-invalid-when-adding-a-service-reference-to-a-sharepoint-odata-service/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Apex 1.2 Released</title><link>http://example.org/apex-1-2-released/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 07:31:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/apex-1-2-released/</guid><description/></item><item><title>MVVM Commanding</title><link>http://example.org/mvvm-commanding/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2011 08:31:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/mvvm-commanding/</guid><description/></item><item><title>MVVM: Asynchronous Commands</title><link>http://example.org/mvvm-asynchronous-commands/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2011 03:51:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/mvvm-asynchronous-commands/</guid><description>private void DoAsyncCommand() { for(int i = 0; i &amp;lt; 100; i++) { // Perform some long operation. string message = DoSomeLongOperation();
// Add the message to the View Model - safely!
asyncCommand.ReportProgress(
() =&amp;amp;gt;
{
messages.Add(message);
}
);
}
}
private ObservableCollection&amp;lt;string&amp;gt; messages = new ObservableCollection&amp;lt;string&amp;gt;();
public ObservableCollection&amp;lt;string&amp;gt; Messages { get { return messages; } }
private AsynchronousCommand asyncCommand;
public AsynchronousCommand AsyncCommand { get { return asyncCommand; } } }</description></item><item><title>SharpGL 2.0 Beta 1 Released</title><link>http://example.org/sharpgl-2-0-beta-1-released/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2011 04:38:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/sharpgl-2-0-beta-1-released/</guid><description/></item><item><title>CodeProject Competition</title><link>http://example.org/codeproject-competition/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2011 07:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/codeproject-competition/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Drawing a DIB Section in WPF</title><link>http://example.org/drawing-a-dib-section-in-wpf/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2011 05:09:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/drawing-a-dib-section-in-wpf/</guid><description>try
{
bitSrc = System.Windows.Interop.Imaging.CreateBitmapSourceFromHBitmap(
hBitmap,
IntPtr.Zero,
Int32Rect.Empty,
BitmapSizeOptions.FromEmptyOptions());
}
catch (Win32Exception)
{
bitSrc = null;
}
finally
{
Win32.DeleteObject(hBitmap);
}
return bitSrc;
}</description></item><item><title>Importing OpenGL Extensions Functions with wglGetProcAddress</title><link>http://example.org/importing-opengl-extensions-functions-with-wglgetprocaddress/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2011 06:57:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/importing-opengl-extensions-functions-with-wglgetprocaddress/</guid><description>private delegate void glMultiDrawArrays (uint mode, int[] first, int[] count, int primcount);/// &amp;lt;summary&amp;gt; /// Invokes an extension function. /// &amp;lt;/summary&amp;gt; /// &amp;lt;typeparam name=&amp;quot;T&amp;rdquo;&amp;gt;The extension delegate type.&amp;lt;/typeparam&amp;gt; /// &amp;lt;param name=&amp;quot;args&amp;rdquo;&amp;gt;The arguments to the pass to the function.&amp;lt;/param&amp;gt; /// &amp;lt;returns&amp;gt;The return value of the extension function.&amp;lt;/returns&amp;gt; private object InvokeExtensionFunction&amp;lt;T&amp;gt;(params object[] args) { // Get the type of the extension function. Type delegateType = typeof(T);
// Get the name of the extension function.
string name = delegateType.</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio Code Analysis - Buffer Overruns</title><link>http://example.org/visual-studio-code-analysis-buffer-overruns/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2011 13:55:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/visual-studio-code-analysis-buffer-overruns/</guid><description>#include &amp;ldquo;stdafx.h&amp;rdquo;
int _tmain(int argc, _TCHAR* argv[]) { // Create two buffers, one small, one large. TCHAR storageSmall[13]; TCHAR storageLarge[128];
// Get a pointer to a string literal.
TCHAR* str = _T(&amp;quot;Here is a string that is too long.&amp;quot;);
// Now do something very dangerous.
::_tcscpy(storageLarge, str);
::_tcscpy(storageSmall, storageLarge);
return 0;
}// Defined in Header2.h static const int LENGTH2 = 128;
// Defined in Header3.h typedef TCHAR LineOne[LENGTH1];
// Defined in Header4.</description></item><item><title>How ISupportInitialize Can Help</title><link>http://example.org/how-isupportinitialize-can-help/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2011 14:49:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/how-isupportinitialize-can-help/</guid><description>I have recently come to discover the ISupportInitialize interface and found that it is extremely useful when developing more complicated WinForms controls.
Here's the link to the interface on MSDN: ISupportInitialize - here I'll describe how it can be useful.
The Problem // openGLControl1 // this.openGLControl1.Anchor = ((System.Windows.Forms.AnchorStyles)((((System.Windows.Forms.AnchorStyles.Top | System.Windows.Forms.AnchorStyles.Bottom) | System.Windows.Forms.AnchorStyles.Left) | System.Windows.Forms.AnchorStyles.Right))); this.openGLControl1.BitDepth = 32; this.openGLControl1.DrawRenderTime = true; this.openGLControl1.FrameRate = 29.41176F; this.openGLControl1.Location = new System.Drawing.Point(12, 12); this.openGLControl1.Name = &amp;quot;openGLControl1&amp;quot;; this.</description></item><item><title>SharpGL 2.0: Hardware Acceleration</title><link>http://example.org/sharpgl-2-0-hardware-acceleration/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2011 07:33:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/sharpgl-2-0-hardware-acceleration/</guid><description/></item><item><title>P/Invoke Performance</title><link>http://example.org/pinvoke-performance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2011 13:09:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/pinvoke-performance/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Trials and Tribulations with SharpGL 2.0</title><link>http://example.org/trials-and-tribulations-with-sharpgl-2-0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2011 06:03:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/trials-and-tribulations-with-sharpgl-2-0/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Solitaire and Spider Solitaire on the CodeProject</title><link>http://example.org/solitaire-and-spider-solitaire-on-the-codeproject/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2011 06:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/solitaire-and-spider-solitaire-on-the-codeproject/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>