<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>OpenShift on dwmkerr.com</title><link>https://dwmkerr.com/tags/openshift/</link><description>Recent content in OpenShift on dwmkerr.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-uk</language><copyright>Copright &amp;copy; Dave Kerr</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 07:15:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dwmkerr.com/tags/openshift/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Integrating OpenShift and Splunk for Docker Container Logging</title><link>https://dwmkerr.com/integrating-openshift-and-splunk-for-logging/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 07:15:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dwmkerr.com/integrating-openshift-and-splunk-for-logging/</guid><description>In this article I'm going to show you how to set up OpenShift to integrate with Splunk for logging in a Docker container orchestration environment.
These techniques could easily be adapted for a standard Kubernetes installation as well!
The techniques used in this article are based on the Kubernetes Logging Cluster Administration Guide. I also found Jason Poon's article Kubernetes Logging with Splunk very helpful.
First, clone the Terraform AWS OpenShift repo:</description></item><item><title>Get up and running with OpenShift on AWS</title><link>https://dwmkerr.com/get-up-and-running-with-openshift-on-aws/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 07:47:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dwmkerr.com/get-up-and-running-with-openshift-on-aws/</guid><description>OpenShift is Red Hat's platform-as-a-service offering for hosting and scaling applications. It's built on top of Google's popular Kubernetes system.
Getting up and running with OpenShift Online is straightforward, as it is a cloud hosted solution. Setting up your own cluster is a little more complex, but in this article I'll show you how to make it fairly painless.
The repo for this project is at: github.com/dwmkerr/terraform-aws-openshift.
Creating the Infrastructure OpenShift has some fairly specific requirements about what hardware it runs on1.</description></item></channel></rss>