<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Web Deploy on dwmkerr.com</title><link>https://dwmkerr.github.io/dwmkerr.com/pr-preview/pr-63/tags/web-deploy/</link><description>Recent content in Web Deploy on dwmkerr.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-uk</language><copyright>Copright &amp;copy; Dave Kerr</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2013 09:22:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dwmkerr.github.io/dwmkerr.com/pr-preview/pr-63/tags/web-deploy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Web Deploy - Could not connect to the remote computer</title><link>https://dwmkerr.github.io/dwmkerr.com/pr-preview/pr-63/publish-web-web-deploy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2013 09:22:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dwmkerr.github.io/dwmkerr.com/pr-preview/pr-63/publish-web-web-deploy/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Using Web Deploy is a nice and easy way to publish websites and web applications with Visual Studio. However, I found one thing that can be a bit of a blocker, that didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be explained anywhere very well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s imagine I administer a webserver that hosts the site &lt;a href="https://www.something.com"&gt;www.something.com&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve installed the Remote Management tools for IIS and the Web Deploy stuff, and have also configured the site to allow Web Deploy. I now try and deploy using Visual Studio, with the settings below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.dwmkerr.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/somesite.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="images/somesite.jpg" alt="somesite" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Validating the connection fails with the message:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;lsquo;Could not connect to the remote computer &amp;ldquo;somesite.com&amp;rdquo;. On the remote computer, make sure that Web Deploy is installed and that the required process (&amp;ldquo;Web Management Process&amp;rdquo;) is started. [more stuff] ERROR_DESTINATION_NOT_REACHABLE.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what do we try first?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 14px;"&gt;Check the Web Deploy feature is installed on the server, it is.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check the Web Management Process is running, it is.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check port 8172 is open, it is.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read up on similar issues, they say the same as the above.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
I spent quite some time pulling my hair out over this - is it because I'm on a different domain? Is there some other port that needs to be open too?
&lt;p&gt;Now the error says &amp;lsquo;could not connect to the remote computer &amp;ldquo;somesite.com&amp;rdquo;&amp;rsquo; - so maybe the issue is here. I try the IP address, &lt;a href="https://www.somesite.com"&gt;www.somesite.com&lt;/a&gt; and the IP address with the port 8172 specified - no joy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turns out, that even though it says &amp;lsquo;Server&amp;rsquo; in the first box (leading us to think it would be the address of a server we need), it&amp;rsquo;s actually the server &lt;strong&gt;with http &lt;/strong&gt;specified. Change the Server from &lt;strong&gt;somesite.com &lt;/strong&gt;to &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.somesite.com"&gt;http://www.somesite.com&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/b&gt;and it works a charm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not the most exciting post ever, but hopefully this&amp;rsquo;ll save someone else wasting the same amount of time that I did.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>CodeProject</category></item></channel></rss>