<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SharpShell on dwmkerr.com</title><link>https://dwmkerr.github.io/dwmkerr.com/tags/SharpShell/</link><description>Recent content in SharpShell on dwmkerr.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-uk</language><copyright>Dave Kerr</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2013 05:40:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dwmkerr.github.io/dwmkerr.com/tags/SharpShell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Context Menu for Trello</title><link>https://dwmkerr.github.io/dwmkerr.com/context-menu-for-trello/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2013 05:40:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dwmkerr.github.io/dwmkerr.com/context-menu-for-trello/</guid><description>I'm on holiday at the moment, back in sunny England. Holiday may not be the right term really, I'm mostly working through charity stuff (for my charity Namaste - Children's Homes Nepal) and company administration. I'm also starting working on a big new project, which is pretty exciting.
Anyway, I got a nice message from a fellow coder George Hahn who has put together a pretty cool project that lets you send files directly to Trello as an attachment to a card, or even as a new card.</description></item><item><title>Creating Info Tip Handlers with .NET</title><link>https://dwmkerr.github.io/dwmkerr.com/creating-info-tip-handlers-with-net/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2013 03:47:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dwmkerr.github.io/dwmkerr.com/creating-info-tip-handlers-with-net/</guid><description>I have just added an article to the CodeProject that discusses how to create Info Tip shell extensions in .NET. These extensions are used by the shell to customise the tooltips shown over shell items.
The article shows how you can use SharpShell to very quickly create these extensions, you can find it at: http://www.codeproject.com/Articles/527058/NET-Shell-Extensions-Shell-Info-Tip-Handlers.
So just how easy does SharpShell make creating Shell Info Tip Handlers? The answer is pretty easy indeed.</description></item><item><title>SharpShell</title><link>https://dwmkerr.github.io/dwmkerr.com/sharpshell/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2013 16:28:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dwmkerr.github.io/dwmkerr.com/sharpshell/</guid><description>SharpShell is a project that I have recently uploaded to CodePlex. This class library, and set of tools and samples, is designed to be a framework to enable rapid development of Shell Extensions using the .NET Framework. In time it may grow to contain some functionality for using Shell entities within managed applications (for example, allowing an Explorer context menu to be built dynamically for a given path).
Anyway, the code is all at sharpshell.</description></item></channel></rss>