<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CSS on dwmkerr.com</title><link>https://dwmkerr.github.io/dwmkerr.com/tags/CSS/</link><description>Recent content in CSS on dwmkerr.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-uk</language><copyright>Dave Kerr</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2018 23:36:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dwmkerr.github.io/dwmkerr.com/tags/CSS/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Procedural Smiles - Animating SVG with pure JavaScript</title><link>https://dwmkerr.github.io/dwmkerr.com/procedural-smiles-animating-svg-with-pure-javascript/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2018 23:36:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dwmkerr.github.io/dwmkerr.com/procedural-smiles-animating-svg-with-pure-javascript/</guid><description>I recently needed to be able to generate a simple face image, with the face being able to scale from happy to sad.
(Why I needed to do this is a long story!)
This gave me the opportunity to have a play with SVG, which is something I've not done in a while and always wished I could spend more time with. You can see the result below, move the slider to see the smile animate:</description></item><item><title>Space Invaders on the CodeProject</title><link>https://dwmkerr.github.io/dwmkerr.com/space-invaders-on-the-codeproject/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 12:24:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dwmkerr.github.io/dwmkerr.com/space-invaders-on-the-codeproject/</guid><description>I'm currently writing a series of articles on the CodeProject called &amp;lsquo;Learn JavaScript&amp;rsquo; and am pleased to say that the latest article is available now!
Learn JavaScript Part 2 - Space Invaders
In this article we take a look at how to create the classic space invaders game with plain JavaScript and HTML - no libraries or frameworks. You can see it in action on the page experiments/spaceinvaders. Check it out - as always, comments are welcome!</description></item><item><title>Introducing Experiments</title><link>https://dwmkerr.github.io/dwmkerr.com/introducing-experiments/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2013 06:00:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dwmkerr.github.io/dwmkerr.com/introducing-experiments/</guid><description>I'm staring a series of articles on learning Javascript (the first is available at http://www.codeproject.com/Articles/642499/Learn-JavaScript-Part-1-Create-a-Starfield). To help with this, I've created the Experiments page. This page will host each of the things I've been playing with in the process of learning JavaScript and coming up with good topics for tutorials.
You can see the Experiments page here, there's also a link at the top of the site. If you like it, please feel free to comment on this post or get in touch.</description></item></channel></rss>