<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Microservices on dwmkerr.com</title><link>http://dwmkerr.com/tags/Microservices/</link><description>Recent content in Microservices on dwmkerr.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-uk</language><copyright>Dave Kerr</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 10:52:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://dwmkerr.com/tags/Microservices/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Death of Microservice Madness in 2018</title><link>http://dwmkerr.com/the-death-of-microservice-madness-in-2018/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 10:52:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://dwmkerr.com/the-death-of-microservice-madness-in-2018/</guid><description>En Español | Reddit Thread | Hacker News Thread
Microservices became a very popular topic over the last couple of years1. &amp;lsquo;Microservice madness&amp;rsquo; goes something like this:
Netflix are great at devops. Netflix do microservices. Therefore: If I do microservices, I am great at devops.
There are many cases where great efforts have been made to adopt microservice patterns without necessarily understanding how the costs and benefits will apply to the specifics of the problem at hand.</description></item><item><title>Get up and running with OpenShift on AWS</title><link>http://dwmkerr.com/get-up-and-running-with-openshift-on-aws/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 07:47:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://dwmkerr.com/get-up-and-running-with-openshift-on-aws/</guid><description>OpenShift is Red Hat's platform-as-a-service offering for hosting and scaling applications. It's built on top of Google's popular Kubernetes system.
Getting up and running with OpenShift Online is straightforward, as it is a cloud hosted solution. Setting up your own cluster is a little more complex, but in this article I'll show you how to make it fairly painless.
The repo for this project is at: github.com/dwmkerr/terraform-aws-openshift.
Creating the Infrastructure OpenShift has some fairly specific requirements about what hardware it runs on1.</description></item><item><title>Creating a Resilient Consul Cluster for Docker Microservice Discovery with Terraform and AWS</title><link>http://dwmkerr.com/creating-a-resilient-consul-cluster-for-docker-microservice-discovery-with-terraform-and-aws/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2017 07:10:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://dwmkerr.com/creating-a-resilient-consul-cluster-for-docker-microservice-discovery-with-terraform-and-aws/</guid><description>In this article I'm going to show you how to create a resilient Consul cluster, using Terraform and AWS. We can use this cluster for microservice discovery and management. No prior knowledge of the technologies or patterns is required!
The final code is at github.com/dwmkerr/terraform-consul-cluster. Note that it has evolved somewhat since the time of writing, see the Appendices at the end of the article for details.
Consul, Terraform &amp;amp; AWS Consul is a technology which enables Service Discovery1, a pattern which allows services to locate each other via a central authority.</description></item></channel></rss>