<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>WordPress on dwmkerr.com</title><link>https://dwmkerr.com/categories/wordpress/</link><description>Recent content in WordPress on dwmkerr.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-uk</language><copyright>Copright &amp;copy; Dave Kerr</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2012 09:04:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dwmkerr.com/categories/wordpress/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Goodbye BlogEngine.NET, Hello WordPress</title><link>https://dwmkerr.com/goodbye-blogengine-net-hello-wordpress/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2012 09:04:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dwmkerr.com/goodbye-blogengine-net-hello-wordpress/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I run my websites on a Windows Server. Years ago, when I started web development, I ran almost exclusively on LAMP (Linux, Apache, MySQL, PHP) setups, which worked great for the sites I was building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I got more involved in commercial development, most of the sites and services I was working on were C#, ASP, IIS and MSSQL Server focused. This is great for web development too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I moved onto a new, Windows based server, I decided that as I was running MSSQL Server and IIS on it, I would move my personal blog onto an ASP based platform - for this I chose BlogEngine.NET.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than one year later, I&amp;rsquo;ve moved to WordPress if you&amp;rsquo;re running sites that need some kind of content management system, it really is one of the best. With lots of support online, regular updates, plugins and themes, a WordPress site generally is easier to maintain and keep looking good than, for example, a BlogEngine .NET site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve also been very impressed with how easy it is to integrate WordPress into existing sites I&amp;rsquo;m updating my site &lt;a href="http://www.childrenshomesnepal.org"&gt;http://www.childrenshomesnepal.org&lt;/a&gt; to have a news section driven by WordPress and it&amp;rsquo;s a breeze - just a little bit of PHP and the posts are there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The short message, so far I&amp;rsquo;m yet to see a better CMS than WordPress for day-to-day use. And that includes Drupal, which is powerful, but a bit of a nightmare to set up (and requires too much IT expertise from contributors to a site).&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>CodeProject</category></item></channel></rss>