<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>JavaScript on dwmkerr.com</title><link>http://dwmkerr.com/tags/JavaScript/</link><description>Recent content in JavaScript on dwmkerr.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-uk</language><copyright>Dave Kerr</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2018 23:36:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://dwmkerr.com/tags/JavaScript/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Procedural Smiles - Animating SVG with pure JavaScript</title><link>http://dwmkerr.com/procedural-smiles-animating-svg-with-pure-javascript/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2018 23:36:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://dwmkerr.com/procedural-smiles-animating-svg-with-pure-javascript/</guid><description>I recently needed to be able to generate a simple face image, with the face being able to scale from happy to sad.
(Why I needed to do this is a long story!)
This gave me the opportunity to have a play with SVG, which is something I've not done in a while and always wished I could spend more time with. You can see the result below, move the slider to see the smile animate:</description></item><item><title>Tips and Tricks for Beautifully Simple Mobile App CI</title><link>http://dwmkerr.com/tips-and-tricks-for-beautifully-simple-mobile-app-ci/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 11:14:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://dwmkerr.com/tips-and-tricks-for-beautifully-simple-mobile-app-ci/</guid><description>In this article I'm going to demonstrate some simple tips and tricks which will help you build and maintain beautifully simple mobile build pipelines. These techniques can be applied to different mobile app technologies and integrated into almost any build system:
Each tip is demonstrated in the sample apps in the dwmkerr/beautifully-simple-app-ci repo.
The Challenges of Mobile App CI Tip 1 - Embrace Makefiles for Consistency Tip 2 - Control Version Numbers with a &amp;lsquo;Touch&amp;rsquo; Command Tip 3 - Control App Icons with a &amp;lsquo;Label&amp;rsquo; Command Tip 4 - Support Configurable App Ids Tip 5 - Document, Document, Document Conclusion The Challenges of Mobile App CI Conceptually, a mobile app CI pipeline is pretty simple:</description></item><item><title>Effective Node.js Debugging</title><link>http://dwmkerr.com/effective-node-js-debugging/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2016 01:36:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://dwmkerr.com/effective-node-js-debugging/</guid><description>If you are interested in improving your Node.js debugging skills, then check out my talk at the recent JSChannel 2016 conference in Bangalore:
Comments and observations are always welcome!</description></item><item><title>AngularJS Promises - The Definitive Guide</title><link>http://dwmkerr.com/promises-in-angularjs-the-definitive-guide/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2014 12:06:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://dwmkerr.com/promises-in-angularjs-the-definitive-guide/</guid><description>Promises are a core feature of AngularJS - whether you understand them or not, if you use AngularJS you've almost certainly been using them for a while.
In this post I'm going to explain what promises are, how they work, where they're used and finally how to use them effectively.
Once we've got the core understanding of promises, we'll look at some more advanced functionality - chaining and resolving promises when routing.</description></item></channel></rss>